<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title></title>
	<link href="https://danwilson.co/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://danwilson.co"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://danwilson.co/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title></title>
		<published>2022-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/now/nov-2022/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/now/nov-2022/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;november-2022&quot;&gt;November 2022&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating my website&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking for work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title></title>
		<published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/now/oct-2022/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/now/oct-2022/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-2021-2022&quot;&gt;October 2021-2022&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recovering from burn out&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Read more poetry</title>
		<published>2021-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/posts/read-more-poetry/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/posts/read-more-poetry/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I used to find books very intimidating. It would take me a days or weeks to just make a dent in one. I used to not be able to see the light at the end of the tunnel, or the wisdom and knowledge that might be waiting for me in a few more chapters. It wasn&#x27;t until I decided to try reading A Game of Thrones that I got used to the discomfort of having a million pages to go. I couldn&#x27;t tell you how long it took me but something changed in my after reading that book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I would read and read and read, never scoffing at how big the book was or how long I had been reading it. Looking back I think it was the amount of shit that was going down. The book was huge, nearly 700 pages, but each page was utilised to the fullest. The wasn&#x27;t bit of information that wasn&#x27;t necessary or repeated. I thought &amp;quot;Maybe reading isn&#x27;t such a time sink after all, look at all this information you can distil from a few pages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of years and my reading habits move from conquering empires to conquering the real world. I switched over to reading mainly non-fiction books, a bit of me was starting to worry about the time sink-ness again and wanted to gain some &amp;quot;real world value&amp;quot; from the books I was reading. Turns out, most books can be blog posts (and most blog posts can be tweets). Do you know what can&#x27;t be reduced down to a tweet? Poetry&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guesthouse by Rumi was shared in a group chat by Paris Rouzati. I&#x27;d never read or even heard of Rumi before. I read over the poem once, then again. Then again. I was amazed that in less than 100 words they were able to convey such a complex message. And yet I&#x27;m reading books on &amp;quot;bigger&amp;quot; subjects that take up twice as many pages as this has words. If you&#x27;re wanting to get as much knowledge in the shortest time possible, read more poetry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently picked up my own poetry book, it was a present from a few years ago. Instead of picking up my main books I decided to dig into some of the words in here. I found that the subject matter is way closer to home than what I&#x27;d been reading my non-fiction. Most poets cover real life problems, most non-fiction books cover the problems you wish you had.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to continue the conversation? Social links are down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Cold showers</title>
		<published>2021-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/posts/cold-showers/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/posts/cold-showers/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years back while on holiday in France, I realised that if I washed my hair in a cold shower it would look great the next day. So for the next two weeks, I had a cold shower every morning. And of course, everyday was a great hair day. I was excited to continue my new hair routine when I got home but I soon found that cold showers in a cold country wasn&#x27;t easy. I quickly went back to hot showers and had to find a new way to get my hair to look good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next I heard of cold showers was when Wim Hof was a guest on the Netflix goop documentary series. Wim was my kind of guy; energetic, fun and young at heart. What he was saying about cold exposure and breathing exercises really resonated with me. It was during a time in my life where I was experimenting with meditation and the spiritual side of life. Over the next year, I would use cold showers to break me out &amp;quot;bad funks&amp;quot;. Days where I was feeling like I needed a pick me up, I would jump in the cold shower. It was a sure fire way to make my body feel alive and connect my mind and body. However, a consistent practice wasn&#x27;t there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&#x27;t until recently that I&#x27;ve been working on consistency. I&#x27;ve been thinking and reading about Wim Hof&#x27;s methods. He says that cold exposure is training your vascular system. It&#x27;s getting your heart to pump blood all the way through your body to stop it&#x27;s temperature from spiraling. After hearing this, I was game for vascular gains. I stepped up my practice to every day, focusing on extending the time in the cold vs how cold I go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From doing this everyday I&#x27;ve come across another small benefit that I&#x27;d like to share with you. It is similar to why people say you should make your bed in the morning. When you make your bed, you&#x27;ve already completed something. Good for you. It gives you a sense of pride you can take throughout your day. A cold shower gives you a similar sense of pride, but instead of being about getting stuff done this one is about fear. You get to experience a little bit of fear (cold water in your face) that you get to look in the eyes and say &amp;quot;Get stuffed!&amp;quot;. Couple that with making your bed and you&#x27;re ready to take on the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to continue the conversation? Social links are down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>My first web project</title>
		<published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/posts/my-first-web-project/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/posts/my-first-web-project/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was shocked to realise that I&#x27;ve been writing code for 10 years now. I remember the first web project I took on. My college class was set out to create a website for a client. By client they meant some local business that needed a brochure website. I had other ideas so I went straight to my film maker friend Lewis Hancock. One of the requirements was to get paid for your work. Lewis, being a film maker, had no money. And me, being a good friend, wanted to make it fair. The deal was set; one website for one copy of Halo 3: ODST. The worst Halo game ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building this website set me on a path of wanting to master the web. Going on to study web application development at university, graduting and getting a job building web sites for a local advertising agency. Looking back at my time there I came to the conclusion that the best thing I built there was a coffee cam that alerted slack where there was fresh coffe. It became clear that I wanted to build more than just brochures. I took some time off work to travel and worked on my skills for building bigger applications. Landing back in the UK I was then given the opportunity to build such applicatoins for money.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I find myself here again, working with Lewis on a new adventure into the metaverse. The first crypto related project I built; The Cabbage Patch (don&#x27;t open on mobile, RIP your data) A collection of artwork by a small community of optimist. Built using NFT Glitch (Made by an optimist Iain Nash) and published to IPFS. The last few months have been a whirlwind tour of crypto, something I&#x27;ve been interested in for a long time but only recently learnt the full potential of. I&#x27;m excited to get working on some projects and master the web 3.0.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to continue the conversation? Social links are down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>I hate not being good at things, but I don’t mind being “Okay” at everything</title>
		<published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/posts/okay-at-everything/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/posts/okay-at-everything/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve always struggled with being bad at things. I’m notorious for it. But something happens to me when I’m terrible at something. I get this deep inner burn that say just one thing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You need to the the best at this right now”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s split second but it has repercussions that can last days to weeks to years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember a morning after a LAN party (back in the day). A friend of mine said we should play golf. “Great” I said. “I’ve never done it before. How hard can it be?” I thought. Fast forward 5 minutes and I sucked. My two friends were fine. They could hit the ball. But me, nope. This was on the weekend and by Tuesday I was in Sports Direct after college buying a golf club and some (golf) balls. I went for a five iron, and I came to that decision on Monday because I’d been Googling it since I got home that Sunday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sports Direct I went to the biggest park I could find and practiced straight away. I spent the next few weeks obsessed until I could successfully smash that ball in a forward direction at a decent speed and height. Other than that, I had no idea about golf.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my golf career. It maybe lasted 4 weeks. Maybe 6 at a push. I still own the golf club. This is a recurring theme in my life. I find something that I can’t do, I get to a place where I’m comfortable doing it, and then it’s over. My drive for it drops. There are obviously things that have stuck. I’m constantly finding new problems with software engineering, I’m still loving to read non-fiction books. After a (very) long hiatus, I’m back skateboarding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s always a worry in the back of my mind, when I do get excited about that new thing. How long is it going to be this time?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to continue the conversation? Social links are down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>My golden child</title>
		<published>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://danwilson.co/posts/my-golden-child/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://danwilson.co/posts/my-golden-child/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I built a coffee cam for my previous job at BJL. It was a Raspberry pi with a camera attached to it. A bash script would take a picture every thirty seconds and post the pictures to an API. The backend was run from Django. And this is where it gets interesting&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django app would receive the picture and crop down just the pot of coffee[1]. Then it would measure how much coffee was in the pot[2]. Again, once we could measure the pot, we could start to use the data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is great for alerts, they have a super simple API and a library for most languages. The simple notifications we came up with “There’s a full pot of coffee” and “The coffee pot needs refilling”. Easy, we know the level of the coffee so we can easily figure out if it needs filling or is nearly full[3]. Great! We have a our IoT things coffee cam from a cheap coffee pot, a raspberry pi with a camera and some technology gaffe tape.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] You’d think I did this with a image recognition library, but that would be the easy option. No I lined the camera and marked where the coffee machine needed to be. And then got the exact cropping measurements I needed from manually cropping the image and saving the coordinates. Then hard coded those values into the crop function. So every time someone moved the coffee machine, everything fucking broke.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Again, you’d think I’d use some line detection here from the bottom of the pot to the level of the coffee. But no, that was the easy option. Instead I turned the whole picture to black and white. Literally, 1s and 0s, pure (255, 255, 255) and (0,0,0). And the amount of coffee in the pot would be proportionate to the amount of black pixels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] As you can imagine, we did it the hard way. We know the amount of black pixels is the amount of coffee. So I got a picture of a 1&#x2F;3 pot of coffee and another of a full pot of coffee. Ran the same code over the pictures that gives me the amount of black pixels and hard coded those bad boys in the notification service. Oh yeah, not even constants. You would have thought I’d learnt from the first time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have other stories about how this was such a terrible system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the moral of the story here is that it doesn’t matter if you miss the mark on your solutions, you’re still getting shit done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some other reasons I loved the project so much:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was useful. It ran for a while, and I used to love seeing the coffee is full notification and getting the fresh coffee someone else made. I don’t think I made coffee for well over a year.
It was totally different to what I was working on day to day. I built a lot of similar projects there and this project was so different from them. If anything, it was my first distributed application.
Following on from number 2, I got paid to do this. I fit this in around my day to day stuff. It made me work really hard on “their” work so I could focus on the fun stuff. I’m not sure if they know just how many hours&#x2F;days I put into this.
It was also the first time I got to work with Joe Sparrow. He was as jazzed as I was about this. And while, he didn’t write any code or anything I don’t think I could have done it with out him. It was as much his project as it was mine. I think it might have been his idea.. but I wrote the code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to continue the conversation? Social links are down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
